NADER NASR

■ nadernasr7@gmail.com ③ www.nadernasr.ca 🧠 (647) 510 - 9223 🧳 Toronto, Ontario in linkedin.com/in/nnasr/ 🗘 NaderNasr

SUMMARY

Front End Web Developer with a solid background in software development with 4+ year within the technology sector. I wanted to enhance my foundational background in JavaScript and be able to continue creating websites that are valuable to end customers. With this goal in mind, I recently completed my Full Stack Web Development Diploma. I enjoy creating applications that are one of a kind, useful and has great purpose for the daily lives of others.

SKILLS

FRONT-END: React, Axios, Webpack, Three.js, Svelte, VueJS, React Native, ThreeJS

BACKEND: Express, PostgreSQL, Node.Js, MongoDB, Firebase LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, SASS

TESTING: Jest, Cypress, Mocha/Chai

VERSION CONTROL: GIT

UI/UX: Fiama, StoryBook, Styled Components, Material UI, Bootstrap, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Adobe InDesign

PROJECTS

Aug. 2022 - Sept. 2022 Traverse

Stack: ReactJs, Axios, Material UI, Google Maps API, Figma

- A travel web application that utilizes Google maps to make it easier for users to discover new attractions, hotels, restaurants in their current location

Aug. 2022 - Aug. 2022

Stack: Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, Tailwind CDN, QRCode.js - A website link QR Generator

July 2022 - Aug. 2022

Stack: ReactJs, Firebase(Authentication, Firestore database, Cloud functions), Material UI - A web app that would shorten links, similar to bit.ly

Mar. 2022 - Mar. 2022 ARt - Commerce

Stack: React Is. PostareSQL. Commerce Is. Node Is. Axios. MaterialUI. Stripe. Model-viewer - An E-commerce application that utilizes augmented reality for art, and wall decorations

EMPLOYMENT

New Idea Machine, Full Stack Developer, Toronto, Ontario (Remote) (Volunteer) Sept. 2022 - Current

Stack: ReactJS, Axios, NodeJs, Postman, Firebase

- · Add new features to applications.
- Collaborating with 10+ developers, designers, and project managers to create a project management website.
- Participating in weekly scrum meetings to ensure project is progressing and barriers are noted and resolved. · Schedule stand-up meetings with team members to review progress, clarify issues and resolve roadblocks.
- Clean up previous code from ES5 to ES6, change function props to deconstructed props and fix bugs and console errors.
- Add more information to the documentation for current and future developers.

OjaBox, Junior Front-End Developer, Dubai, UAE

Worked closely with client, product managers and designers to conceptualize new features with building the company website to create a new online platform that offers users the ability to create, share, purchase, and sell various 3D content and VR Assets for use within the auamented reality industry.

Designed, developed and launched the company website including a content library and 3D rendering tool using Three.js

Added marketing analytics tools eg. Google analytics.

• Launched the OjaBox website using Reactjs, AWS, NodeJs, ThreeJs, Material UI

360VUZ, Technical Project Manager, Dubai, UAE

Aug. 2016 - Jan. 2018

Managed 2 remote mobile development teams in India and a web development team in Ukraine in creation of the 360VUZ mobile application that broadcasts live concerts and events to the subscriber using the Oculus Gear VR. Administered the project budget, tracked expenses, monitored performance, and ensured milestones were met

Collaborated with the client to establish technical direction, introduce functions, and gain consensus on changes.

Key Achievements:

· Achieved the original launch deadline date by overcoming various technical issues without affecting

performance and helped grow downloads from 50,000 in the first year to over 500,000 in the second year by optimizing the functionality

Rubicon Group Holding, Junior Virtual Reality Unity Developer, Amman, Jordan

Mar. 2014 - Mar. 2016

Developed applications and educational games for the Oculus Gear VR using Unity 5

Liaised with team members throughout the software development lifecycle to achieve established milestones

• Created an interactive digital comic book for kids using Unity 5 that could be played on their mobile devices

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs

Jan. 2022 - Apr. 2022

Diploma Full Stack Web Development

Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2018

Certificate Full Stack Web Development

Advanced Diploma Interactive Media Design

Aug. 2011 - Aug. 2014